{
    "id": "fb756f47acf745cfbb31629ad59ff39a",
    "title": "Mixed Conditionals Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "If I don't drink tea in the morning, I ............................. sleepy.",
            "description": "We can use the zero or first conditional here because we are talking about a real and possible situation. In the zero conditional, we use a simple present tense in both clauses and in the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the result clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "feel",
                "will feel",
                "would feel",
                "would have felt"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If she arrived, we ......................... her with open arms.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will receive",
                "would receive",
                "would have received"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I ....................... you if you say that word again.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, we use a simple present tense in the if-clause and will + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will beat",
                "would beat",
                "would have beaten"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had been there, I ................................. you.",
            "description": "In the third conditional, we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will help",
                "would help",
                "would have helped"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If I were you, I ............................... this.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "won't buy",
                "wouldn't buy",
                "wouldn't have bought"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If I had time, I ......................... dinner.",
            "description": "In the second conditional, we use a simple past tense in the if-clause and would + infinitive in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will cook",
                "would cook",
                "would have cooked"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I would handle the situation differently, if I ..................... angry.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "am't",
                "weren't",
                "hadn't been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you heat ice, it ...........................",
            "description": "In the zero conditional, we use a simple present tense in both clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "melt",
                "melts",
                "will melt",
                "would melt"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had tried harder, you ...............................",
            "description": "In the third conditional we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will succeed",
                "would succeed",
                "would have succeeded"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "If you try hard enough, you .........................",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "will win",
                "would win",
                "would have won"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If she ....................... now, we can have dinner together.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "arrives",
                "arrived",
                "would arrive"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "If you ........................ there, you could meet him.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "went",
                "had gone"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        }
    ]
}